DAMJAN KOLEVSKI

Product Design Engineer

+389 70 277 552
damjan.kolevski@gmail.com
damjankol.github.io/portfolio



with a bachelor's degree of Industrial Design in Mechanical Engineering, and five years of experience in that field, as well as an academy of UX Design, and a current work experience in the IT Industry - SaaS for Smart Manufacturing/Industry 4.0.

His strongest professional competences are: Research, Front End Programming, New product development, CAD, Mechanical Engineering, Project management, Developing department procedures, Design and execution of Manufacturing Technologies, Continuous improvement (Kaizen), LEAN culture (5S, Kanban), On-time results, International teamwork, Dynamic workflow.

Industries he experiences: IT. Healthcare, Smart Manufacturing, Sport, Hospitality,

Personally, he is described as: committed, honest, reliable, enthusiastic, creative, details-oriented, communicative, adaptable, patient, tolerant.



DIGITAL COMPETENCE

- Adobe XD, Figma, InVision, Miro (Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototypes)
- Photoshop, Illustrator (Graphic Design)
- HTML, CSS, JS (Front End Programming)
- Solidworks, AutoCAD, MAYA, CATIA
 (3D assembly modelling & 2D technical drawing)
- ProCast, Matlab, Adams (Dynamic simulations)
- 3ds MAX (Animation)

WORK EXPERIENCE

UX Design Engineer

ATS GLOBAL, Industry: IT, SaaS, Industry 4.0 Apr. 2021 - Present, Skopje

- User Researching, User Tests (with Userlytics)
- Mapping User Flows (with Miro)
- Designing Wireframes (with InVision)
- Designing Prototypes (with Figma)
- Implementing Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)
- Planning a development of Design System
- Working in Agile environment (with Azure DevOps)

R&D / CAD Mechanical Engineer

CRANFIELD FOUNDRY, Industry: Foundry Jan. 2019 - Sep. 2020, Probishtip

Development Engineer

CASTINVEST, Industry: Foundry Feb. 2018 - Oct. 2018, Skopje

Business Developer

REGEMAT 3D, Industry: Healthcare Aug. 2017 - Jan. 2018, Granada

Assistant to CEO

KOPLAST, Industry: Plastic Mar. 2015 - Jul. 2017, Skopje

Graphic Designer & Events Organizer

Macedonian Canoe Federation, Industry: Sport Mar. 2014 – present (part-time), Skopje

EDUCATION

BRAINSTER Academy of UX/UI Design

Jul. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Pre-program/Graphic Design (Photoshop, Illustrator)
- Fundamentals of UX/UI Design
- Tools: AdobeXD, Figma, InVision (Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototypes)
- Design Systems, Responsive Design
- Front End Programming (HTML, CSS, JS)
- Storytelling, Pitching

MOTIVA Management Training

Feb. 2013 - Mar. 2013

Communication Skills; Developing and Managing Effective Teams; Entrepreneurship, Developing SMEs, Writing Business Plan; Financial Mgmt.; Leadership and Business Negotiation; Strategic Mgmt. and Business Ethics; Export Marketing; Presentation Skills; Change Mgmt.; Human Resources Mgmt.; Quality Mgmt.

University Ss. Cyril & Methodius in Skopje, Bachelor of Mech. Engineering in Industrial Design

Sep. 2011 - Jan. 2015

- Mechanical Engineering,
- New Product Development,
- 3D assembly modelling & 2D technical drawing (Solidworks, AutoCAD, MAYA, CATIA),
- Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing,
 Design for Manufacturability, Material Properties
- Graphic Design (Photoshop),
- Dynamic Simulation (Matlab, Adams),
- Animation (3ds MAX),
- Web Design/HTML/CSS (Dreamweaver)

Vocational Courses

- IBM: Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner (August 2021)
- IDF: User Research Methods and Best Practices (July 2021)
- IDF: Conducting Usability Testing (June 2021)

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- age: Millennial
- languages: English (fluent), Spanish (intermediate), French (beginner), Macedonian (mother tongue) Bulgarian (fluent), Croatian (fluent), Serbian (fluent).
- driver's license: B category (active driver)
- hobbies: Painting, Photography, Architecture, Folklore, Ecology, Humanitarian Volunteering, Tennis, Skiing, Volleyball, Hiking, White-water kayaking, Karate, Scouting, Dancing, Ice-skating, Table-tennis, Billiard, Ultimate Frisbee, Playing Piano, Flute...